<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Korean-Myths on k-vibe</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/korean-myths/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Korean-Myths on k-vibe</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>ko-kr</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/korean-myths/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Duffy the Haechi: A Korean Myth Story</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/duffy-the-haechi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/duffy-the-haechi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/kvibe-thumbnail-20250928-111235.png&#34; alt=&#34;Duffy the Haechi&#34; title=&#34;Duffy the Haechi: A Korean Myth Story&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Are you ready to dive deep into the fascinating world of Korean mythology, especially when it features a character as cool as **Duffy the Haechi** (해치) from &amp;ldquo;K-Pop Demon Hunters&amp;rdquo;? Trust me, this isn&amp;rsquo;t just a fun character; it&amp;rsquo;s a window into the heart of Korean culture, a guardian of justice whose stories have been passed down through generations like precious heirlooms. Growing up in Korea, these mythical creatures weren&amp;rsquo;t just illustrations in old books; they were almost like invisible friends, always there, subtly influencing our understanding of right and wrong, much like how your favorite K-drama heroes inspire you today.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dokkaebi: Goblin: More Than Just a Demon</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/dokkaebi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/dokkaebi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/kvibe-thumbnail-20250825-123205.png&#34; alt=&#34;Dokkaebi&#34; title=&#34;Dokkaebi: Goblin: More Than Just a Demon&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome, K-VIBE fam! Are you ready to dive deep into the fascinating world of Korean mythology? If you&amp;rsquo;ve ever found yourself captivated by a supernatural love story in a K-drama or thrilled by the thought of mystical beings, then you absolutely need to meet the **Dokkaebi (도깨비)**. These iconic Korean mythical creatures are not your typical Western ghosts or demons. Oh no, they are far more complex, intriguing, and dare I say, *human-like*.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dangun Story: Unyielding Korean Soul</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/dangun-story-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/dangun-story-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/kvibe-thumbnail-20250823-030215.png&#34; alt=&#34;Dangun Story&#34; title=&#34;Dangun Story: Unyielding Korean Soul&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;dangun-story-단군신화-the-enduring-spirit-of-koreas-founding-myth&#34;&gt;Dangun Story (단군신화): The Enduring Spirit of Korea&amp;rsquo;s Founding Myth&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ever found yourself captivated by a K-drama character’s unwavering resolve, or marveling at a K-pop idol’s journey from a hopeful trainee to a global superstar? If you’ve wondered what fuels that incredible drive, that seemingly endless wellspring of perseverance, you’re in for a treat. Today, we&amp;rsquo;re diving deep into the very heart of Korean identity, reaching back to a story whispered through generations, a myth that is so much more than just a tale: the &lt;strong&gt;Dangun Story (단군신화)&lt;/strong&gt;. This isn’t just about ancient gods and magical bears; it&amp;rsquo;s about understanding the foundational spirit that continues to shape modern Korea, from its resilience in the face of adversity to its spectacular cultural triumphs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Korean death messenger folklore: Saza boys?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/korean-death-messenger-folklore/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/korean-death-messenger-folklore/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/6_black_boys-1-1024x559.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;Korean death messenger folklore: Saza?&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Prepare to have your perception of the afterlife transformed, because today we&amp;rsquo;re diving deep into the fascinating world of **Korean death messenger folklore (저승사자 이야기)**, a realm far richer and more complex than any simple &amp;ldquo;grim reaper&amp;rdquo; you might imagine. Forget the hooded, scythe-wielding figure you know from Western tales. Korea&amp;rsquo;s afterlife guides, the *저승사자* (jeoseungsaja), are a captivating blend of solemn duty, sartorial elegance, and, believe it or not, bureaucratic charm. Growing up in Korea, these stories weren&amp;rsquo;t just spooky tales; they were intricate narratives woven into our cultural fabric, shaping our understanding of life, death, and what truly matters. From ancient myths to blockbuster K-movies and even K-pop stages, the *저승사자* has evolved into an iconic figure, capturing the imaginations of global audiences and offering a unique window into the Korean psyche.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Sibling who became the Sun and the Moon</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-sibling-who-became-the-sun-and-the-moon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-sibling-who-became-the-sun-and-the-moon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/kvibe-thumbnail-20250823-022306.png&#34; alt=&#34;The Sibling who became the Sun and the Moon&#34; title=&#34;The Sibling who became the Sun and the Moon: The Sibling Who&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hey, K-VIBE fam! Have you ever looked up at the sun and the moon and wondered about the incredible stories they might hold? In Korea, we certainly do! Many cultures have myths about these celestial bodies, but there&amp;rsquo;s one particular Korean tale that has not only shaped our understanding of the cosmos but also deeply woven itself into our everyday language and cultural consciousness. Get ready, because today we&amp;rsquo;re diving into the enchanting world of **The Sibling who became the Sun and the Moon (해와 달이 된 오누이)**!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
